Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- TIME'S UP! NYC Direct Action Environmental Organization Archived Website, Oct 26, 2009 - ongoing; Time's Up (New York, N.Y.)
  Direct action |z New York (State) |z New York.; Environmentalism -- New York (State) -- New York.; Green movement |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Trayvon Martin Organizing Committee Archived Website, Jul 16, 2013- ongoing; Trayvon Martin Organizing Committee
  The Trayvon Martin Organizing Committee is an organization that advocates for justice for Trayvon Martin. Martin was fatally shot by George Zimmerman on February 26, 2012. Zimmerman was tried on June 24, 2013, and found not guilty the following day. The organization believes that Martin's death was a race based murder and Zimmerman was not arrested because of white supremacy and classism inherent in the criminal justice system. The website contains information about rallies in response to the not guilty verdict, as well as reports from the rallies' aftermath.
  Discrimination |z United States.; Martin, Trayvon, 1995-2012
- U.S. Department of Defense. Military Commissions Combatant Status Review Tribunals Archived Website, Jul 8, 2009; U.S. Department of Defense. Military Commissions Combatant Status Review Tribunals
  United States Department of Defense Combatant Status Review Tribunals/Administrative Review Boards site contains CSRT/ARB Special Interest Items, Biographies of key DOD personnel, High Value Detainees CSRT Information including for each, unclassified summaries, transcript and audio of hearings, procedural instructions, news releases, and current briefing transcripts.
  Torture |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- U.S. Department of Defense. Military Commissions Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009 - Nov 5, 2014; United States. Department of Defense
  United States Department of Defense Detainees Investigations. Contains "Special Reports, " Independent Panel Reports, Department of the Inspector General Report, all from 2004--2005
  Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- U.S. Department of Defense. Military Commissions Brief Transcripts Archived Website, Jul 30, 2009; United States. Department of Defense
  Briefing transcripts, 2004--2005
- U.S. Department of Justice Office of the Inspector General Semiannual Report to Congress: April 1, 2008-September 30, 2008 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of the Inspector General
  Contains an Office of the Inspector General report to Congress regarding the Federal Bureau of Investigations involvement in and observation of detainee interrogations in Guantanamo Bay, Afghanistan, and Iraq.
  Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.
- U.S. Department of Justice Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- June 2008 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy
  Contains summaries of the court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by Office of Information Policy during the month of June 2008.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners of war, American.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Law and legislation.; Torture |z United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- U.S. Department of Justice Summaries of New [Federal Court] Decisions -- October 2008 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy
  Contains summaries of the court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by Office or Information Policy during the month of October 2008.
- U.S. Department of Justice Summaries of New Court Decisions -- September 2009 Archived Website, Nov 30, 2009; United States. Department of Justice. Office of Information Policy
  Contains summaries of the court decisions pertaining to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp that were received by Office of Information Policy during the month of September 2009.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Law and legislation.; Torture |z United States.; Military interrogation -- United States -- Evaluation.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- Union Square Awards Archived Website, Aug 1, 2011 - Jan 7, 2014; Union Square Awards
  The Union Square Awards, established in 1998, awards grants to social activists, community organizers, arts organizations, and other activism in New York City. Over $16 million has been distributed to 238 organizations, since the awards founding. The website contains information on past awardees, grants, and award programs.
- United for Peace and Justice Archived Website, Oct 1, 2007 - ongoing; United for Peace and Justice (Organization)
  United for Peace and Justice, founded in 2002, is a coalition of more than 1400 local and national groups that organizes opposition to U.S. military involvement in Iraq and Afghanistan, against nuclear weapons, and for economic and social justice. The website contains action alerts, news listings, event listings, and other resources.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Protest movements -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.
- United Neighborhood Houses of New York, Mar 17, 2012 - ongoing; United Neighborhood Houses
  United Neighborhood Houses of New York, founded in 1919, is a collective of settlement houses that promotes neighborhood-based, multi-service approach to improving the lives of New Yorkers in need and their communities. The organization provides services for youth, children, immigrants, seniors. One of their main focuses also includes housing stability, which provides community building in public housing and advocates for programs to prevent homelessness. The website contains event listings, news, programming, and advocacy campaigns.
- United States. Congress. Senate. Armed Services Committee Report: Inquiry into the treatment of detainees in U.S. custody, 11/20/2008 Archived Website, Sep 28, 2009; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Armed Services
  United States. Congress. Senate. Armed Services Committee. Inquiry into the treatment of detainees in U.S. custody, 11/20/2008
  Human rights |z United States.; Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- US Peace Council Archived Website, Feb 29, 2012- ongoing; US Peace Council
  Founded in 1979, the US Peace Council is a multi-racial, pro-working class, anti-imperialist organization committed to peace, economic and social justice and to international solidarity with the peoples of the world. The group promotes the prohibition of all weapons of mass destruction, the abolition of foreign military bases, universal disarmament under effective international control, and negotiations instead of use of force in the settlement of differences between nations. It is affiliated with the World Peace Council, the world's largest peace organization and an NGO member of the United Nations. The website contains resources, news, petitions, issues of focus, and information on chapters.
  Anti-imperialist movements.; Peace movements -- United States.; Social justice.
- Veterans For Peace Archived Website, May 11, 2011- ongoing; Veterans for Peace, Inc.
  Veterans For Peace is a veterans educational and humanitarian organization dedicated to the abolition of war, founded in 1985. The website contains a newsroom, action alerts, resources, and personal accounts by members.
  Peace movements -- United States.; Veterans -- Political activity -- United States.
- veteransforpeaceny Archived Website, Dec 21, 2011-Jun 22, 2013; Veterans for Peace, Inc.
  This is the New York chapter of the Veterans for Peace Organization.
  Veterans -- Political activity; Veterans -- New York (State) -- New York; Peace movements -- New York (N.Y.)
- War Resisters League Archived Website, Oct 1, 2007- ongoing; War Resisters League
  War Resisters League, founded in 1923, is a secular pacifist organization that challenges military recruitment, organizes and trains for nonviolent direct action, and offers on-the-ground education. Their projects include the GI Resistance Support Project, the Bite the Bullet: War Profiteering Education and Action Network, the quarterly magazine WIN: Through Revolutionary Nonviolence, advocacy of and support for war tax resistance, demonstrations, and local and regional anti-war organizing projects. The website contains information on chapters, publications, resources, news, and event listings.
  Peace movements -- United States.; Pacifism -- United States.
- Weather Underground FBI Report 1976 Archived Website, Aug 9, 2009; United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation
  The Weather Underground Organization, also known as Weathermen, described itself as a revolutionary organization of communist men and women. The FBI's analysis of its motivations, beliefs, and international travels are outlined in this 420 pp. summary, released under the Freedom of Information Act.
  Communists -- United States.; Terrorists |z United States.; New Left -- United States.; Weather Underground Organization
- Wellstone Action Archived Website, Jan 8, 2012- ongoing
  Wellstone Action, founded in 2003 and named for the late Paul Wellston (formerly U.S. Senator from Minnesotta) and Sheila Wellstone, is a national center that provides training and leadership development in the progressive movement. The organization works to train underrepresented communities to engage in civic life. Wellstone trains campaign workers, candidates, activists, students, domestic and sexual violence advocates, labor organizers and unions, Native American community leaders, and non-profit leaders.
  Public interest lobbying.
- Witness against Torture: A Campaign to Shut down Guantanamo Archived Website, Jul 8, 2009- ongoing; Witness against Torture
  At our inception, with the December 5-17, 2005: Walk to Guantanamo to Visit the Prisoners, Witness Against Torture was a group of friends who-- as Americans and Catholics-- walked to Guantanamo to visit the prisoners, to perform a work of mercy, to respond to the victims of the war on terrorism. Once we returned from that journey, we began to organize more broadly to shut down Guantanamo, working with interfaith, human rights and activists' organizations. We have planned a series of nonviolent direct actions to expose and decry the administration's lawlessness, build awareness about torture and indefinite detention amongst Americans and forge human ties with the prisoners at Guantanamo and their families.
- Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (WILPF) Archived Website, Mar 8, 2010- ongoing; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom
  The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom was founded in 1915 during World War I, with Jane Addams as its first president. WILPF works to achieve through peaceful means world disarmament, full rights for women, racial and economic justice, an end to all forms of violence, and to establish those political, social, and psychological conditions which can assure peace, freedom, and justice for all. WILPF works to create an environment of political, economic, social and psychological freedom for all members of the human community, so that true peace can be enjoyed by all.
  Women and peace.; Feminism; Peace movements
- Women's International League for Peace and Freedom NY Metropolitan Branch Archived Website, Sep 15, 2012- ongoing; Women's International League for Peace and Freedom. New York Metropolitan Branch
  The Women's International League for Peace and Freedom was founded in 1915 during World War I, with Jane Addams as its first president. WILPF works to achieve through peaceful means world disarmament, full rights for women, racial and economic justice, an end to all forms of violence, and to establish those political, social, and psychological conditions which can assure peace, freedom, and justice for all. WILPF works to create an environment of political, economic, social and psychological freedom for all members of the human community, so that true peace can be enjoyed by all. This is the New York City branch website.
  Peace movements; Women and peace.; Feminism
- Women Occupy Archived Website, Jun 13, 2013- ongoing; Women Occupy
  Women Occupy is a feminist organizing group, established by CODEPINK: Women for Peace, affiliated with the Occupy Wall Street Movement. The group works to aggregate and create resources of relevance to women and allies committed to confronting patriarchy, heterosexism, and transphobia. They also provide women with resources for creating safer spaces and feminist organizing for general assemblies. The website contains resources for organizing, a discussion forum, and a news blog.
  Feminism -- New York (State) -- New York.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Workers Solidarity Alliance Archived Website, Apr 19, 2009- ongoing; Workers Solidarity Alliance
  Workers Solidarity Alliance is an anti-capitalist, anti-authoritarian organization of activists who believe that working people can build a new society and a better world based on the principles of solidarity and self-management. WSA also publishes ideas and action, which was created in July, 1981 as an independent anarcho-syndicalist semi-annual print magazine. After Workers Solidarity Alliance was founded in November, 1984, ideas and action became the magazine of WSA (with issue #5), and continuing through the publication of issue #17 in 1997. It now exists as a blog on the WSA website.
  Working class -- United States.; Labor unions -- United States.; Anarchism -- United States.
- Workers World Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009- ongoing; Workers World Party.
  Workers World is the newspaper of the Workers World Party, a Marxist-Leninist communist party of Trotskyist orientation.
  Trotskyism |z United States |v Periodicals.; Communism -- United States -- Newspapers.
- Workers World Party Archived Website, Jul 31, 2009- ongoing; Workers World Party.
  Workers World Party was founded in 1959 as a Marxist-Leninist Party. The party advocates for a mass movement led by workers to promote socialism and end the United States two party system. The website contains international and national news, news on anti-war movement, immigrant rights, the economy, gay rights, the environment, prisoner rights, anti-racism, women's rights, and other news. The website also contains editorials, books, and their Spanish version of the website, Mundo Obrero.
  Trotskyism -- United States.; Communism -- United States.
- Working Families Party Archived Website, Sep 23, 2007 - ongoing; Working Families Party (N.Y.)
  Founded in 1998, the Working Families Party (WFP) is New York progressive political party formed from community organizations, neighborhood activists, and labor unions. The party's main issue concerns are jobs, health care, education and energy/environment. The organization cross-endorses candidates who support their platforms. The website lists endorsed candidates, issues, and action alerts.
  Labor movement -- Political activity -- United States.; Political parties |z New York (State).
- Workmen's Circle / Arbeter Ring Archived Website, May 3, 2009- ongoing; Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring
  Founded in 1900, The Workmen's Circle / Arbeter Ring fosters Jewish identity and participation in Jewish life through Jewish, especially Yiddish, culture and education, friendship, and the pursuit of social and economic justice. The organization was formed by Jewish immigrants to face challenges of assimilating to the new culture and fighting labor practices, and was rooted in the labor and socialist traditions.
  Yiddish language -- Social aspects -- United States.; Jews -- United States -- Societies, etc.
- World Socialist Web Site Archived Website, Apr 27, 2012- ongoing; World Socialist Web Site
  The World Socialist Web Site (WSWS) is the online news and information center of the International Committee of the Fourth International (ICFI). The site publishes articles and analysis covering a wide range of topics and events all around the world with a socialist slant. The daily 'Perspective article presents the position of the WSWS on a wide range of political, theoretical, and historical issues. The website includes news on social inequality, workers' rights, and art criticism. WSWS also includes sections on history, philosophy, documents from the Marxist Library, and letters from readers.
  Trotskyism.
- Young Communist League USA Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009- ongoing; Young Communist League of the U.S.
  The Young Communist League, USA is a multi-racial, working-class organization made up of youth who believe we can build a better world. We come from a variety of backgrounds, just like the young people of our country: we are employed and unemployed workers, we are high school and college students, we are Black, white, Latino, Asian, and Native American, we are gay and straight, we are women and men. The YCL is associated with the Communist Party of the United States of America.
  Youth movements -- United States.; Socialism and youth -- United States.; Communism -- United States.
- Young Democratic Socialists Archived Website, Nov 25, 2008- ongoing; Young Democratic Socialists.
  Young Democratic Socialists (YDS) is the youth affiliate of the Democratic Socialists of America, founded in 1983. YDS organizes on college campuses to fight for the immediate needs of workers and students, while building the capacity to fight for more radical and structural changes in the long term. The website contains information on their student chapters, their coordinating committee, current platforms, which include student debt relief and labor solidarity, news and multimedia, and their blog, the Activist.
  Socialism and youth -- United States.; Democratic Socialists of America
- Young People's Socialist League Archived Website, Aug 10, 2009-Nov 13, 2010; Young People's Socialist League
  The Young People's Socialist League (YPSL), established in 1913, is the youth affiliate of the Socialist Party, USA. The website contains organizing tools, their constitution and principles, and a message board. The site became defunct in 2010.
  Socialism and youth -- United States.; Socialist Party (U.S.)
- Young People's Socialist League Reunion Archived Website, Sep 28, 2007-May 8, 2008; Young People's Socialist League Reunion.
  This website was formed in connection with a 2007 reunion in New York City of members of the Young People's Socialist League. The YPSL, as it was commonly known, was the youth group affiliated with the Socialist Party (U.S.) Many of its members allied themselves with the views of Leon Trotsky.
  Trotskyism -- United States.; Socialism and youth -- United States.; Socialist Party (U.S.)
- Zuccotti Park Press Archived Website, Nov 27, 2012- ongoing; Zuccotti Park Press
  Zuccotti Park Press is the website for the Occupy Wall Street Movement's pamphlet series, taking the name from the park where the protest took place in fall 2011. The website features digital versions of their pamphlets.
  Pamphlet series (New York, N.Y.).; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).